<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on James&#39; Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on James&#39; Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>James Gan | Personal Portfolio | 2020&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Path Finding Visualisation using A* Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/path-finding-astar-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/path-finding-astar-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>Personal Project - The goal of undertaking this project was 3 prong. (1) Apply my knowledge in A* Path Finding algorithm,(2) Structure the code with Object Oriented Programming(OOP) technique and (3) Document the process with software architecture design.
The project was built with Python and utilised the Python package PyGame to build the visualisation.
 Screenshot of the A Star Path Finding Algorithm Program Project  Table of Contents:  A* Path Search Algorithm Overview Usage Viewing Files in this Repository Lessons Learnt and Conclusion Acknowledgment  .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory Analysis of Data Science and Analytics Job Market in Singapore 2020</title>
      <link>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/job-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/job-market/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Personal Project - As graduation approaches, I decided that it would be beneficial to get an overview of the Data centred jobs in Singapore. Therefore, I decided to scrap the popular job site, Glassdoor, to gather data on the jobs on the market and have the bigger picture of the job market.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Approach to Titanic Accident</title>
      <link>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/titanic-accident/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/titanic-accident/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Personal Project -  I undertook this project during the start of the penultimate year summer break to hone my knowledge in statistics and analytical thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identified features with statistical hypothesis test such as ANOVA, Chi-Sqaured Test and Bonferroni Method with R.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Achieved 75% prediction accuracy on Kaggle Competition with Gradient Boosting Classifier algorithm in Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimising Warehouse Resource Allocation</title>
      <link>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/psa-warehouse-allocation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/psa-warehouse-allocation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Industry Attachment Project - This project was my university industry attachment with PSA International PTE LTD in conjunction with two university modules: (1) Statistics and (2) Manufacturing and Supply Chain Operations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of Manufacturing Process Bottlenecks</title>
      <link>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/tsh-manufacturing-bottleneck/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/tsh-manufacturing-bottleneck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Industry Attachment Project - This project was my university industry attachment with TSH Synergy PTE LTD in conjunction with  university modules: Data and Business Analytics. By creating a Business Intelligence Dashboard and Data Analysis to expedite the identification of possible bottlenecks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevator Crowd Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/dw-elevator-crowd-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/dw-elevator-crowd-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;University Academic Project - This project was an academic project for my first programming module in University. The project utilised electrical engineering knowledge alongside Python programming knowledge to develop a product that consists of a Graphical User Interface(GUI) where users can interact with to gain information on the crowd in the elevator. And a electrical circuit system consisting of trip wires and ultrasonic sensors to allow us to derive the flow of users of the elevator and the floor on which the elevator is serving&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>