<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>James&#39; Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content on James&#39; Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>James Gan | Personal Portfolio | 2020&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/education/</guid>
      <description>Singapore University of Technology and Design May 2018 to Aug 2021  Bachelor of Engineering in Engineering Systems and Design, Honours Major in Business Analytics, with a Minor in Artificial Intelligence Recipient of Singtel Exchange Undergraduate Scholarship (SHINE Program) Notable Courses: Statistics, Optimisation, Probability &amp;amp; Data and Business Analytics  Zhejiang University May 2019 to Aug 2019  Semester Exchange Recipient of Temasek Foundation international (TFi) Scholarship Took courses in Principles of Big Data and Design - User Experience  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills</title>
      <link>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/skills/</guid>
      <description>Programming  Python - pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Plotly, Sci-Kit Learn, Statsmodel, spaCy, Beautiful Soup, Selenium Scala Spark 2.0 Hadoop R - tidyr, ggplot2, mlr SQL Git Bash  Enterprise Software  Microsoft Excel Tableau Desktop and Prep Builder Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop  Academic Knowledge  Statistics Optimisation Machine Learning Algorithm Neural Networks  Certificates    Course Issuing Organisation     Neural Networks and Deep Learning Coursera   Hadoop for Big Data Udemy   Spark 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shopee Code League Hackathon 2020</title>
      <link>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/shopee-code-league/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/shopee-code-league/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br&gt;
Industry Hackathon - In my penultimate year, I took part in Shopee&#39;s Code League Hackathon 2020 which was for the first time completely held online due to the novel coronavirus situation. The challenge was held over the course of 8 week where there were 8 challenges that overlapped each other in the field of data science, machine learning, data analysis and natural language processing. [Link](https://careers.shopee.sg/codeleague/) to the hackathon page.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Path Finding Visualisation using A* Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/path-finding-astar-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/path-finding-astar-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>Personal Project - The goal of undertaking this project was 3 prong. (1) Apply my knowledge in A* Path Finding algorithm,(2) Structure the code with Object Oriented Programming(OOP) technique and (3) Document the process with software architecture design.
The project was built with Python and utilised the Python package PyGame to build the visualisation.
 Screenshot of the A Star Path Finding Algorithm Program Project  Table of Contents:  A* Path Search Algorithm Overview Usage Viewing Files in this Repository Lessons Learnt and Conclusion Acknowledgment  .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work Experience</title>
      <link>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/workexperience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/workexperience/</guid>
      <description>DataSpark - Data Science Intern June 2020 to Sep 2020  Under Singtel SHINE Programme Identified high value customer segment of business through feature engineering using Spark 2.0 written in Scala. Validated key business metrics utilised by product mangement team through test cases written with SparkSQL. Improved quality of data with development of Outlier Detection Algorithm utilising DBSCAN and ARIMA models.  Eatigo - Operations Intern Feb 2018 to March 2018  Managed Salesforce to coordinate the requirements of merchants and users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory Analysis of Data Science and Analytics Job Market in Singapore 2020</title>
      <link>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/job-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/job-market/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Personal Project - As graduation approaches, I decided that it would be beneficial to get an overview of the Data centred jobs in Singapore. Therefore, I decided to scrap the popular job site, Glassdoor, to gather data on the jobs on the market and have the bigger picture of the job market.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extra-Curricular Activities</title>
      <link>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/eca/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/eca/</guid>
      <description>Competitions    Name Issuing Organisation Title Year     Shopee Code League Shopee Participant 2020   Smart City Challenge GovTech &amp;amp; DBS Participant 2019   DBS Design Challenge DBS 1st Place 2018   UBS GCOO Case Challenge UBS Participant 2018    University Societies    Society Name Role Role Summary Years Active     Volleyball Player Not Applicable 2020-2021   University Ambassador Member School Ambassador for external and internal events 2018-2020   Student Government Director of Public Relations Handled sponsorships deals and external collaborative events 2018-2019   Mountaineering Club Member Not Applicable 2018    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/about/</guid>
      <description>James Portrait  Passionate about tech. Striving to make this world a better place.
Hello there! I&#39;m a Business Analytics Major with a Artificial Intelligence Minor at Singapore University of Technology and Design(SUTD).
Throughout the my education journey, I had the privilege of leading various groups such as the Vice-Head Prefect in Secondary School, Vice-Captain of Cross Country Club in Junior College and the Director of Public Relations for the Student Government for University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m available for coffee or a zoom session!(:
   Platform URL     Portfolio Website: https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/   Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jamesgsw/   Github: https://github.com/jamesgsw   Kaggle: https://www.kaggle.com/jamesgsw   Email: james_gan@mymail.sutd.edu.sg   Phone Number: +65 90279661    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Approach to Titanic Accident</title>
      <link>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/titanic-accident/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/titanic-accident/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Personal Project -  I undertook this project during the start of the penultimate year summer break to hone my knowledge in statistics and analytical thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identified features with statistical hypothesis test such as ANOVA, Chi-Sqaured Test and Bonferroni Method with R.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Achieved 75% prediction accuracy on Kaggle Competition with Gradient Boosting Classifier algorithm in Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimising Warehouse Resource Allocation</title>
      <link>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/psa-warehouse-allocation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/psa-warehouse-allocation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Industry Attachment Project - This project was my university industry attachment with PSA International PTE LTD in conjunction with two university modules: (1) Statistics and (2) Manufacturing and Supply Chain Operations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of Manufacturing Process Bottlenecks</title>
      <link>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/tsh-manufacturing-bottleneck/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/tsh-manufacturing-bottleneck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Industry Attachment Project - This project was my university industry attachment with TSH Synergy PTE LTD in conjunction with  university modules: Data and Business Analytics. By creating a Business Intelligence Dashboard and Data Analysis to expedite the identification of possible bottlenecks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevator Crowd Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/dw-elevator-crowd-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesgsw.github.io/James-Portfolio/projects/dw-elevator-crowd-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;University Academic Project - This project was an academic project for my first programming module in University. The project utilised electrical engineering knowledge alongside Python programming knowledge to develop a product that consists of a Graphical User Interface(GUI) where users can interact with to gain information on the crowd in the elevator. And a electrical circuit system consisting of trip wires and ultrasonic sensors to allow us to derive the flow of users of the elevator and the floor on which the elevator is serving&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>